Guide to the Records of the Ukrainian St. Peter and Paul Orthodox Church (Willimantic, CT) r.7
Ukrainian Historical and Educational Center Archives
The Ukrainian St. Peter and Paul Orthodox Church (Willimantic, Conn.) Records
1930-1976
r.7
Ukrainian Historical and Educational Center Archives
1.2 Linear feet 20 bound volumes, 4 folders
The St. Peter and Paul parish was founded in the early 1930s during the height of the Great Depression, and remained active for approximately 40 years. The collection contains lists of parish members and records of baptisms, marriages and funerals, as well as legal records, deeds, and parish council meeting minutes dating back to the founding of the parish.
Ukrainian St. Peter and Paul Orthodox Church (Willimantic, Conn.).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 4 series as follows:
Membership records
Financial records
Parish council records
Register books
Conditions Governing Access
Access and use of this collection may be subject to restrictions. Please contact the archivist (archives@ukrhec.org) for more information and to make arrangements.
Biographical/Historical note
The St. Peter and Paul parish appears to have been founded in the early 1930s during the height of the Great Depression by Ukrainian immigrants. It remained active for approximately 40 years, and was liquidated in the 1970s due to declining membership numbers. The membership appears to have been primarily pre-WWII immigrants and their descendents.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains lists of parish members and records of baptisms, marriages and funerals, as well as legal records, deeds, and parish council meeting minutes dating back to the founding of the parish in the 1930s.
Baptismal registers; Deeds; Funeral registers; Legal documents; Marriage registers; Parochial records; Ukrainian American churches--Connecticut--Willimantic
- Membership records, 1933-1975; Series 1.; 2 bound volumes
  - Volume 1, 1933-1955
  - Volume 2, 1959-1975
- Financial records, 1937-1976; Series 2.; 0.8 Linear feet 12 bound volumes, 1 folder
  - Income and expense ledgers, 1937-1976; 0.5 Linear feet 6 bound volumes
    Scope and Contents
    Some records appear to be duplicated between ledger books.
    - Volume 1, December 1937 - December 1949 (Volume 3)
    - Volume 2, January 1948 - December 1950, January 1953 - March 1954, January - July 1955 (Volume 4)
    - Volume 3, January 1950 - December 1959 (Volume 5)
    - Volume 4, January 1960 - December 1965 (Volume 6)
    - Volume 5, January 1966 - December 1971 (Volume 7)
    - Volume 6, January 1972 - April 1976 (Volume 8)
  - Check stubs, 1952-1976; 0.3 Linear feet 6 bound volumes
    - Volume 1, 1952-1958 (Volume 9)
    - Volume 2, 1958-1963 (Volume 10)
    - Volume 3, 1963-1967 (Volume 11)
    - Volume 4, 1967-1970 (Volume 12)
    - Volume 5, 1970-1974 (Volume 13)
    - Volume 6, 1974-1976 (Volume 14)
  - Miscellanous receipts, 1956-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Parish council records, 1932-1976; Series 3.; 2 bound volumes, 1 folder
  - Legal records, Bulk, 1933-1946; 1933-1960 (Oversize 1, Box 1, Folder 2)
    Certificate of organization, bylaws, deeds, mortgage documents, tax exemption forms, and cemetary deeds.
  - Meeting minute books, 1932-1938, 1973-1975; 2 bound volumes
    - Volume 1, 1932-1938 (Volume 15)
    - Volume 2, 1973-1975 (Volume 16)
  - Loose pages, 1933-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Meeting minutes, correspondence, and parish closing records.
- Register books, 1930-1973; Series 4.; 4 bound volumes, 1 folder
  - Baptism records, 1930-1968; 2 bound volumes (Volume 17-18)
  - Matrimonial records, 1939-1970; 1 bound volume (Volume 19)
  - Funeral records, 1939-1973; 1 bound volume (Volume 20)
  - Loose pages, 1933-1967; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Baptism records, plus one matrimonial record from 1937.